

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

□ 0406436117 | ■ benrogers1299@outlook.com | ★ www.benrogers.dev | 回 ben04rogers | 匝 ben-rogers-a3b013140

About Me_

I currently work as a web developer for an e-commerce marketing agency called M3 Digital on a temporary contract and am looking for a more permanent role in software development consulting. I am a final semester (July 2022) student completing a bachelor's degree in information technology at QUT, with a major in computer science. I am a high achieving student with a GPA of 6.15/7 at university. I have been learning programming for over 4 years ever since I was in high school and I love it. I am very passionate about all aspects of software development and cloud computing. In my spare time I love tinkering with technologies and learning new things.

Skills

Front-end JavaScript, React.js, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Shopify Liquid, jQuery

Back-end Python, C#, Java, SQL, Node.js, Express, MySQL, REST APIs

Practices Database design, TDD, Agile, Scrum, OOP, software design patterns, web design, BEM

Tools/Software AWS, Git, Linux, Jira, Adobe Creative Cloud, Figma, Shopify, Microsoft 365

Education

Queensland Univeristy of Technology (QUT)

GPA: 6.15/7

Mar. 2018 - June. 2022

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

- Major in Computer Science
- · Minor in Networks and Security
- Minor in Mobile Applications

Experience

M3 Digital
Web Developer (temp contract)

Brisbane

September, 2021 - Present

Dec. 2018 - June. 2021

Worked on variety of Shopify stores such as FitazFK, Rider Collective, Masseuse Massage, Francesca Jewellery and Salty Captain.

- Developed custom front end features and sections using HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, and Liquid.
- Developed high quality landing pages from scratch with modular CSS and JS practices for maintainability.
- Integrated many third party plugins within existing stores, e.g. Calendly for customer bookings and Preezie for product recommendations.
- Used Git version control to manage projects.
- · Fixed front end bugs.

Retail Safari Brisbane

Microsoft Product Advisor

- Contracted by Microsoft to represent them in retail stores.
- Demonstrating Microsoft products to customers Windows, Surface, Office and Xbox.
- Troubleshooting Windows and Microsoft Office related software issues.
- Training JB Hi-Fi and Harvey Norman staff on products and the key selling points for each.
- Tracking customer preferences through daily data collection and reporting.

Programming Projects

CryptoCrowd Sentiment Analysis

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uhyC0M4WIl4

- Cryptocurrency sentiment analysis based on Twitter posts.
- React.js front end and Node.js back end.
- Used the 'sentiment' npm module which is a AFINN based sentiment analysis library.
- Stateless application that uses Elasticache and S3 on AWS for persistence.
- Application was setup with an auto scaling group to scale in and out as needed.

Organisational Asset Trading

https://github.com/ben04rogers/organisation-asset-trading

- · Worked on a team of four students to develop a client-server system in Java for trading of virtual assets with departments of a company.
- Facilitated trades via a marketplace model where users can buy and sell assets.
- Users can login and view sell history, their listings, a summary, all listings, an assets list, their account information, their credits and they can also change their password.
- Admin users can create assets, modify assets, modify credits and add new users to the system.
- Used MariaDB for the database and Swing for the GUI.
- Tested extensively with JUnit and created detailed documentation.
- Implemented sockets and threads for the server.
- · Used build scripts to run unit tests when deployed.

Country Happiness Application

https://trusting-babbage-96d918.netlify.app/

- Used React.js and Bootstrap to develop a site that interacts a REST API that I made which holds happiness data collected from the World Happiness Report initiative.
- Users can register, login and view happiness data by country.
- Users can also filter data by year, country and search limit using react-select dropdowns.
- AG Grid and Chart.js were used to present the data.
- · Backend used Node.js, Express and MySQL.
- Security features such as use of Knex, Helmet, Morgan and bycrypt.js.
- · Tested extensively with Jest.

Computer Auction Website

https://iab207-assessment-3.herokuapp.com

- Used Python, Flask, SQLite and Bootstrap to develop a computer auction site.
- · Users can register, login, create new listings, bid on listings, search by keyword, manage listings, post reviews and keep a watch list.
- Used Flask WTForms, Flask SQLAlchemy and Flask Login.

References

Tai Reedy (0449557285)

Microsoft Master Trainer / Content Creator for Retail Safari (contracted by Microsoft)

• Tai was my area manager for over a year and supervised my work.

Mandeep Saini (0449544118)

Microsoft Market Manager for Retail Safari (contracted by Microsoft)

- Worked alongside Mandeep as a Microsoft Product Advisor for over 2 years.
- Mandeep was my manger up until I left the role.